STAR TREK
STRANGE
NEW
WＯRLDS
SEASON 01  #  EPISODE 09
"All Those Who Wander"
Previously. on STAR TREK STRANGE NEW WORLDS...
HEMMER: The Aenar believe the end only comes...
once you have fulfilled your purpose.
It provides meaning.
- So. what was your purpose?
To fix what is broken.
What do you feel is the purpose of your life's path?
I really don't know.
I apologize...
for the incident on the bridge...
between Nurse Chapel and I.
I never actually believed you could have feelings...
for Nurse Chapel.
LA'AN: The Gorn captured my family's colony ship.
When they hunt. they're unrelenting.
Plenty of people have seen the Gorn.
They just don't live long enough to talk about it.
UHURA: Cadet's Personal Log. Stardate 2510.6.
My assignment to Enterprise is over.
After we complete our current mission...
delivering vidium power cells to Deep Space Station K-7...
I go back to Earth.
I'm excited to see my grandmother.
Our last call was cut short.
Life on a starship has a way of taking over.
I've rotated through almost every department.
So many amazing. talented people.
The top everyone of everything.
They all know why they belong in Starfleet.
For them. Starfleet has always been the destination.
For me...
it was where I ran to after the loss of my parents.
Serving aboard Enterprise is an affirmation...
of this entire crew's hopes and dreams.
I envy their surety.
But...
me...
I guess I'm still searching.
PIKE: Time to bend some ears.
Welcome to the big send-off.
Although they leave us in a couple of weeks. today it's official.
Let's hear it for Cadets Chia and Uhura for completing...
their training rotation on the U.S.S. Enterprise.
[APPLAUSE]
You have both been exemplary crew members.
Dedicated.
Hardworking.
Collaborative.
We've seen some things together.
- MAN: Yeah. we have.
[LAUGHTER]
- We've survived some things together.
[SCATTERED CHUCKLING]
- Hmm.
We are bonded now and forever...
by the family that is Starfleet.
And speaking of bonds and oaths...
Ensign Duke. front and center.
Effective immediately. you are no longer an Ensign.
Congratulations. Lieutenant Duke.
[LAUGHTER. APPLAUSE]
[LAUGHS]
[QUIET CHATTER]
All this time on the ship. and you still shy away from the crowd?
Permission to speak freely. sir?
Nyota. it's me.
Live it up. it's a party.
It's your party.
Yes. permission granted.
I hate goodbyes.
Still haven't decided to stay?
I know better than to beat a dead horse...
but you've made an impact here.
There will always a place on Enterprise for Nyota Uhura.
[COMMS CHIRPING]
- SPOCK: Spock to Captain Pike.
What is it. Spock?
Incoming priority 1 mission from Starfleet Command. sir.
Spock out.
- [COMMS CHIRPING]
Aren't we already a priority 1 mission?
Yeah.
Where's La'An?
- She couldn't make it. She's...
scheduled personal health time.
She can join us in progress.
Get Science and Medical.
They need to send someone else.
It's not someone else's assignment.
Sorry I'm late. I was with Dr. Sanchez again.
Head shrinker.
It's called Starfleet Recovery Assistance...
and I'm glad you're making use of it.
You're on time. We're just kicking around...
some intel on a mission brief.
While you clean up?
People are capable of doing 2 things at once.
Spock?
- Approximately 4 days ago...
the U.S.S. Peregrine activated a distress beacon...
before losing contact.
Can you take over the dishes for a minute?
Oh. Yes. of course.
Saved you a plate.
- No. thanks. I'm not hungry.
You're gonna want to try the omelet and the bacon.
And the waffle.
PIKE: The Peregrine's deep space relay...
took 2 days to reach Starfleet.
Another 2 to us. so we might still have contact. just delayed.
Oh. my God. this is delicious.
- Told you.
At the time of transmission. the Peregrine was making...
an unscheduled emergency landing on a Class-L planet.
Valeo Beta V.
Are emergency landings ever scheduled?
The ship made its descent...
but its beacon went out mid-transmission.
Destroyed on impact? Where... Uh. do you have the... Where's the...
Extra cheese?
- Mmm.
While possible. it is more likely...
the interference on Valeo Beta V has disrupted the signal.
The upper atmosphere is littered with charged nitrate ions.
UNA: Planet's a known dead zone.
Our communications and transporters don't reach the surface.
A Sombra-class ship. that's unique.
I served on one. Fast.
Built with the same parts as a Constitution.
She'd gone off the grid. gathering data in uncharted sectors.
The Federation wants us to aid the crew and. if possible...
retrieve the ship.
And our current mission?
The vidium power cells for K-7.
Without them the whole space station goes dark.
Including life support.
The nearest ship that could deliver them for us...
is a week away.
SPOCK: Vidium cells decay in transport.
A delay of that duration would render them all useless.
I advise we send a landing party...
to make repairs and treat the wounded.
Meanwhile. Enterprise can continue on to deliver the vidium.
Like you said. sir.
People are capable of doing 2 things at once.
Let me get you some bacon.
It's risky.
There's no way the landing party could contact the ship.
True. it is a communications dead zone...
but I have faith in our crew to get it done.
The Enterprise can pick us up on the way back.
Us?
- PIKE: I'll oversee this one personally.
Get the cadets out on 1 last away mission...
with Senior Officers.
You sure you want to split up the crew?
It'll be fine. Number One.
You get the supplies to K-7...
I'll pile the kids in the station wagon. take a road trip.
Sir? The station wagon?
Anybody has to go. now's the time.
Do not make me turn this car around.
Okay. You have your orders.
[OVER COMMS] Number One. you're good to go.
We're making our descent now.
UNA: We'll monitor your approach.
PIKE: That's a negative. Once we enter the upper atmosphere...
we're going to be out of contact...
[DISTORTED] Make haste to K-7.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[WIND WHISTLING]
Man. this is gonna be a hike.
Geothermal anomalies have forced us to land...
several kilometers from the Peregrine.
We should work quickly. This area is highly volatile.
It is due to be overrun by an ice storm...
in approximately 6 hours.
This wind...
reminds me of Andoria.
[LAUGHS]
- [EXHALES]
Glad someone can enjoy it.
The anomalies. is that what's killing our comms?
Negative. Ensign.
It is the ionic interference...
that prevents long-range communication.
Drink. You owe him a drink. Spock.
Duke's a Lieutenant now.
Call him an Ensign. you got to buy him a drink.
Starfleet tradition.
Another human drinking game.
Does their number have no limit?
Nope.
M'BENGA: Based on these readings...
the Peregrine made landfall near the ridge of a great chasm.
No life signs. anything?
[TRICORDER BEEPING]
Still too much interference.
PIKE: We should be getting something.
LA'AN: Captain.
Might not be a scanning problem.
STAR TREK
STRANGE
NEW
WＯRLDS
SEASON 01  #  EPISODE 09
"All Those Who Wander"
PIKE: Space.
The final frontier.
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
Its 5-year mission...
to explore strange new worlds...
to seek out new life...
and new civilizations...
to boldly go...
where no one has gone before.
[ ♪ THEME MUSIC ♪ ]
♪♪
[STATIC]
[CLANGS]
[WIND WHISTLING]
[METAL GROANING]
Blood.
SPOCK: Captain. there's more blood over here as well.
I want a full diagnostic. As fast as you can.
Any luck on the internal comms?
No. Still down.
And environmental systems are at 20%.
Captain. the bridge is completely offline.
Someone hardwired all the controls down to Engineering.
Why would they do that?
HEMMER: Plasma in the main circuits.
That's not typical.
They were likely using energy from the warp core injectors...
as emergency power.
But that would imply...
UHURA: No backup batteries.
And the matter-antimatter reactor's busted.
Clearly I brought the right people for the job.
Hem. can you fix it?
- Perhaps.
I'll have to work in Engineering.
Mr. Spock. can you manage restoring bridge functions?
I will attempt to make quick work of it.
[CLATTERING]
It's grim.
20 casualties so far. 1 of them the Captain.
The Peregrine has a crew of 99.
There could be more we didn't find.
Most died of hypothermia.
Their suits are shredded by the elements.
Some of them were picked apart. maybe...
local wildlife.
Maybe something else.
As far as I can tell...
the crew went outside. got caught in a brutal storm...
and couldn't find their way back to the ship.
Pull up the logs.
I bet it's real creepy here after dark.
It's already pretty damn creepy.
CHIA: Lieutenant Kirk. We found something.
What the hell did this?
I can only get audio.
GAVIN: Captain's Log. Stardate...
I'm not even sure.
A week since we've crashed?
Peregrine was mapping non-Federation space...
when we found 3 castaways on an M-Class planet.
A human girl. a humanoid of unknown origin...
and an Orion named Pasko.
We rescued them. Brought them aboard.
But we didn't know what we didn't know.
Pasko was infected with Gorn eggs.
Biofilters didn't detect them.
But the Orion knew.
He set off a plasma grenade in Engineering...
tried to end it.
The system sent an automatic distress call...
in response to the explosion.
If I could reach Starfleet now. I would say
"Stay away."
"Don't come to Valeo Beta V."
A little late for that. isn't it?
M'Benga. Spock. go get the others.
GAVIN: But if you're watching this...
chances are we didn't survive.
La'An.
What do you want to do?
- I want to kill them.
But I'd settle for finding any crew alive...
and getting off of this frozen rock.
Captain. ops are coming online.
I have 2 life signs on Deck 5.
Human or Gorn?
UHURA: 1 human...
the other...
unknown.
Hemmer...
keep powering up whatever you can.
And. La'An. Uhura. you're with me.
[WEAPON POWERING UP]
This body's been badly mangled.
[CLATTERING]
[WEAPON POWERS UP]
[GROWLS]
Kakalaka jarfuk pikarak!
PIKE: What's he saying?
Universal translator isn't processing it.
Uhura. do something.
That's not how linguistics works.
Karfuk. Karfick. Karfarsh.
Wait.
It's 2 life signs. right?
Shipa. Shipa.
UHURA: He might be protecting someone.
We should lower our weapons.
[WEAPON POWERS DOWN]
Stand down.
[GROWLS SOFTLY]
I hope you're right about this.
[WEAPON POWERS DOWN]
UHURA: We're friends.
We're here to help you.
And whoever might be with you.
[GROWLS SOFTLY]
♪♪
[GRUNTS SOFTLY]
SPOCK: Nurse Chapel...
I need dermal synthesizers for a burn wound.
Where? You look fine.
Lieutenant Duke.
He did not account for potential instabilities...
in the Jefferies tube.
Duke wasn't paying attention.
Indeed.
Although I do fail to see the logic in asking me...
to come for supplies instead of seeking treatment.
Mmm. well...
Duke made rank. Spock.
He's acting tough.
Pride. A flawed human emotion.
It's called foolish for a reason.
Thankfully. the teachings of Surak allow me to purge such things.
One does not take pride in logic.
I understand that. uh. Vulcans have a strong. hidden primal nature.
I bet you're a tempest when you're angry.
It is true that without proper mindfulness
Vulcan emotion is dangerous.
We use logic to not succumb to anger.
It's good to get mad sometimes.
UHURA: I'm gonna miss you. Hemmer.
- HEMMER: Nonsense.
People tend to find their way back around in Starfleet.
Mmm... Not me.
When you asked me about my life path...
I didn't have an answer.
So I had to ask myself...
"Uhura. why don't you have an answer?"
And what was Uhura's response?
I've just been drifting.
It's time for me to stop coasting.
And you feel that serving with Starfleet is coasting?
[CHUCKLE SOFTLY] I don't know.
Maybe.
Who knows where I'll end up.
But...
I'm not afraid to face it alone anymore.
Interesting.
I never felt that your fear was being alone.
I think your problem is the exact opposite.
Oh. really? Please. enlighten me.
You make friends easily. when you allow it to happen.
You think I don't like making friends?
No. I think you love it.
And deep down. that scares you. 'cause...
your real fear is putting down roots.
So now you're a Ship's Counselor?
[SCOFFS] I understand.
It is better to leave than to be the one left behind.
But that's wrong.
You create bonds. It's a gift.
Of course the people you care about are going to cause you pain...
it will hurt...
but the love it yields will far outweigh the sorrow.
Now. hand me the electron coupler.
Piti titi camu.
Topa karfarsh. Piki shipa topa.
M'BENGA: Your friend...
what's his name?
I call him Buckley.
I like it.
It's just what I call him.
What's your name?
- Oriana.
Are we getting out of here?
Are you checking them thoroughly?
Readings don't show any anomalies.
Are you infected?
Is he?
I told you the readings are clean.
Where are the Gorn?
- Karfika kafk!
It's okay. Buckley. I got this.
The monsters are gone.
Why didn't you tell the Captain about the Gorn eggs...
when they saved you?
Why did you stay quiet?
Lieutenant.
- You could've saved them.
La'An. stop harassing my daughter.
My patient.
Leave her alone.
Find somewhere else to be useful.
PIKE: Sensors show the ship is clean.
Whatever happened outside seems to be the end of it.
Reported missing 2 years ago.
Help me understand.
Where do the Gorn fit in?
The girl and the 2 aliens were probably refugees...
from a breeding planet.
The adult Gorn only harvest their young sporadically...
so whatever was born on this ship. they are most likely alone.
Don't take comfort in that. Captain.
They're equally lethal on the ground.
It only takes 1.
Comms are still down. but we can do a security sweep.
If there are any still alive down here.
A soprano sings in E minor...
and we associate a feeling.
But it's not really about the melody.
Our own reflections make it emotional.
I'm not being emotional.
I was talking about me.
I called the girl my daughter.
But that girl...
Oriana...
she's in a place few can understand.
Before pain twists her up inside...
she has a chance to grow beyond it. like you.
There's no magic button you press. You just...
You just survive.
She just needs someone to help her see the light.
[WEAPON POWERS UP]
[CLATTERING IN DISTANCE]
[RATTLES]
[CLATTERING CONTINUES]
[WIND BLOWING]
- [CLATTERING]
♪♪
Sorry. That for Lieutenant Duke?
Oh. I didn't realize you were so jumpy.
[WHEEZING]
[MUFFLED HEART BEATING]
Elevated heart rate.
[GROANS]
Hello. What is this now?
Chia. pass me that light.
- Yep.
Chia. can you calibrate for a physical?
Just use the readings we took on him before.
Kalaka. Pika. Kalaka.
- CHAPEL: Easy.
Just gonna run a quick simulation on your scans.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[GASPING]
♪♪
You all right up there?
[CONTINUES GASPING]
[MUFFLED RUMBLING]
[SCREAMING]
[GROANING]
Nurse Chapel?
[SCREECHES]
- [SCREAMING]
[SCREAMING]
[CHOKING]
- [SQUEALS]
[SQUEALING]
[BREATHING SHAKILY]
[CLANGS]
- [SQUEALING]
[GORN CLUCKING]
[BEEPS. WHIRS]
You were lucky. Those conduits had a full current.
[CLATTERING NEARBY]
M'BENGA: Be glad.
I could be amputating.
DUKE: Great.
1ˢᵗ mission as a Lieutenant. and I almost lose an arm.
Don't beat yourself up. These things happen. All right?
Duke. perhaps if you take comfort in the fact...
that you completed the needed repairs.
That will shape your pride...
- [GROWLING]
[SCREAMING]
[GORN CHITTERING]
PIKE: Sam. grab him. Keep him still.
[SCREAMING]
There's 2 of 'em.
Hold him down. I don't want to risk hitting him.
[SCREAMING]
[SCREAMING STOPS]
We need to alert the rest of the crew.
Right now.
[WHISPERS] Oriana?
[BEEPS. WHIRS]
[EXHALES]
[MUTTERS]
♪♪
[BREATHING SHAKILY]
[WHISPERS] Oriana?
[LOUD CLATTERING]
- [GASPS] It's you.
Oh. thank God. [SIGHS]
They came out of him.
I... I didn't see where...
The girl.
4 Gorn hatchlings.
I count 1 dead. that leaves 3.
They'll mature soon. and then fight for dominance.
What do we do?
Scan for biosignatures.
Okay.
Still no comms.
I've hits on our people. but nothing on the Gorn.
Does that mean they're gone?
I doubt it. Somehow they found a way to avoid our sensors.
So they could be anywhere.
Take this.
Watch the ceilings. shoot anything that moves.
Yeah.
[WEAPON POWERS UP]
LA'AN: We need to find that girl.
This is where she was before.
[CHAPEL WHISPERS] Oriana?
Nothing.
[CLATTERING IN DISTANCE]
Nice hiding spot.
Hey. we're here to keep you safe.
She's already safe.
Gorn hate the cold.
It's why you came back here. isn't it?
Coldest place in the ship?
It's where I'd hide.
ORIANA: People before you tricked them into going outside.
But now they're back.
We leave here. we die.
[ECHOING] Run!
My brother died like your friend.
The Gorn got him.
I know what it feels like...
to watch them hurt the people you love.
You feel alone.
Nobody understands the pain.
But look at me now.
These people I came with...
my job is to keep them safe.
And this crew. I believe we can do anything...
even defeat the Gorn.
Oriana. trust me.
There's surviving and then there is living.
Come on.
[WHIRRING]
Now. once we hit the relay switch...
the systems will begin to cycle...
and then we just have to reboot navigation.
Team Hemhura strikes again. huh?
You may have the honor.
[ALARM WAILS]
[ALARM STOPS]
- [GROWLING IN DISTANCE]
What is that?
I don't know. [SNIFFS]
But I smell human blood.
Power's on. Means Hemmer's making progress.
We stay in here. we're lizard chow.
We got to make a run for the shuttles.
By my calculations. the ice storm outside has just begun.
It is not safe to leave the ship.
It isn't safe inside the ship.
But. hey. at least we'll all die nice and warm.
Sam. you saw I hurt one.
We can fight them.
[GRUNTS IN FRUSTRATION]
[SIGHS]
I could give him a sedative.
No. Sam's tougher than he looks.
And I need everyone alert.
Captain. the internal comms are back online.
Open a channel. all decks.
[ALERT WAILS. CHIMES]
PIKE: All hands. emergency protocol...
regroup and rendezvous in Sickbay.
Repeat. get to Sickbay and watch your 6.
[CLANGS]
- [GASPS]
[GROWLING. CLUCKING]
[GROWLS]
We need to make a run for it.
No!
Aah!
- Hemmer!
[GROANING]
- [SNARLS]
[SCREECHES]
M'BENGA: Medical Officer's analysis.
SPOCK: Fascinating.
The Gorn's biological makeup renders them invisible...
to all of our sensors.
A genetic chameleon.
That's how I missed them inside of Buckley.
Is there anything from his bio scan we can use?
Something trackable?
M'BENGA: For starters. we don't even know what kind of species he was.
And according to this...
the maturity cycle depends on the host.
In the Orion. it took weeks.
Humans. days.
These ducts in the mouth likely expel venom.
Yes. and it burns quite tremendously.
No doubt a toxin meant to blind its victims.
I was not the best target.
Hemmer. I know you have rules about telepathy.
Any chance they don't apply to an enemy...
that's trying to eat us?
If I could. I would.
But it appears they have a psychic barrier to my abilities.
I cannot sense them.
Impressive. Like their genetic coding.
No doubt another evolution in order to hunt undetected.
Impressive?
You think this is impressive?
It was merely an observation.
He killed Duke right in front of you. Spock.
Doesn't that hit you. somewhere deep inside?
No? Nothing?
We just need to reboot navigation.
Can you feel anything?
Or are you just some heartless. pointy-eared computer?
Hey!
Now that that's out of the way...
if we want get out alive...
we have to stop yelling at each other and start listening.
Hemmer.
What is it you're trying to tell us about the nav-comm?
It's the only system left to reboot.
Everything else is online.
That means our mission is complete.
That would be correct.
Okay. Now let's get rid of these Gorn.
La'An. tactical analysis.
The hatchlings have begun molting...
but they aren't fully mature.
At this stage. younglings have an intense drive...
for alpha dominance.
The 2 left will be the strongest. the smartest...
and extremely hostile to each other.
That's a weak spot.
We can work together. that's our advantage.
No matter what. we have to kill them now.
We'd have no chance even against 1 adult Gorn.
These younglings move too fast for us to hunt.
We'll have to create a choke point.
The Gorn are highly intelligent. even at this stage.
A simple trap won't work.
How are we supposed to hunt them?
We can't even track them with sensors.
We make them come to us.
That is very logical.
LA'AN: Gorn can't resist aggressive behavior.
They won't back down from a challenge...
so we can use that to draw them out. put them down.
Great. Now we're bait.
LA'AN: We can use the environment controls.
Gorn avoid the cold.
We can force them into the areas we want them in.
Now. this sounds like the start of a plan.
All right.
Let's get to work.
[SPARKS CRACKLING]
[POWERING UP]
Computer...
transfer all functions to comms station.
Captain Pike...
command code 2-4-6-8-10.
You still haven't changed that?
PIKE: We can quarterback the operation from here.
COMPUTER: Temperature decreasing.
As the ship cools. this bay will become a warm oasis for them.
You are okay with what you must do?
If it succeeds. you and I will be trapped in here...
with angry Gorn.
I will not be the one to kill it...
but I will do what I must to protect the lives of this crew.
Hey. Are you okay?
Trust me. there's nothing I'd rather be doing right now...
than fighting back against the Gorn.
UHURA: Game on.
[CLATTERING]
[GROWLING. CLUCKING]
It's here.
[CLUCKING]
[SHRIEKS]
We got one in the chute!
[SHRIEKING. CLUCKING]
Uhura. I'm blasting the Transporter Room now.
Go!
Come on. come on.
[PANTING]
You really are good at everything.
[CLUCKING]
PIKE: It's going into the vent system. Spock. get into position.
[WEAPON POWERS UP]
[DISTANT GROWLING]
[FEET CLATTERING]
[LOW CLUCKING]
It's not responding.
PIKE: You have to draw it out.
LA'AN: Fight it. Spock! Make it angry!
[SCREAMING]
The rage that is in my thoughts...
I let into my heart.
[SHOUTING]
[CLUCKING]
- [GRUNTS]
[GORN CHITTERS]
[GORN CHITTERING]
PIKE: Why does my audio sound like there are 2 Gorn?
The other one is here. It's boxing him in.
PIKE: Spock. watch for the 2ⁿᵈ Gorn.
[GORN SHRIEKS]
[SHRIEKS]
Hey. hey. easy. easy. It's me. It's me.
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
[GORN SHRIEKING IN DISTANCE]
SAM: They've turned on each other.
[SHRIEKING CONTINUES]
When those 2 are finished there'll be 1 left.
The alpha.
We put that down. we go home.
[WEAPON POWERS UP]
Hemmer...
I'm coming your way.
[LOW GROWLING. CLUCKING]
Come on!
[CLATTERS]
I'm unarmed.
It's just you and me.
Fight me! Come on. fight me!
[ROARS]
[GROWLING]
[SHRIEKS]
[SHRIEKING]
Hemmer. now! Do it now!
♪♪
[SHOUTING]
[EXHALES]
It's dead. Chris.
Yeah?
[GRUNTING]
We did it. That's the last of them.
Not quite.
I'm going to go outside now.
[GROANING]
Hemmer. what's going on?
I may not be able to sense them...
but I know my own body very well.
The spray. It's more than a venom.
It's how they reproduce.
Captain. open the door.
PIKE: I... I can't.
I do not want anyone to try to stop me.
We can extract them.
We'll neutralize the growth process...
figure something out.
If we had more time. I'm sure you could.
But it's too late to... [GROANS]
We all know what's coming.
Hemmer. you don't have to do this.
But. Captain...
my sacrifice...
will save the lives of those I care most about.
For me. there is no other choice.
[GROANS]
A logical conclusion.
Live long and prosper. my friend.
No. No! We can help you. [POUNDS ON DOOR]
You have to let us try.
[CHUCKLES SOFTLY] Uhura.
I want to leave you with 1 last piece of advice.
Open yourself.
Make a home for yourself amongst others...
and you will find joy more often than sadness.
Hemmer.
[VOICE BREAKING] Hemmer. please. please...
HEMMER: Do not weep for me.
[SOBBING]
I've had a good life.
[WINCES]
It's time for me to go.
♪♪
[UHURA CONTINUES SOBBING]
[GRUNTING]
[GRUNTS SOFTLY]
Just like Andoria.
[SQUELCHING]
♪♪
ORTEGAS: This sucks. I hate funerals.
But if Hemmer was here. he would remind us...
that this is a celebration.
"Exalt the fallen and commit them to the cosmos."
Then he would have scolded me for pushing the engines too hard.
And I would have called him a Blue Meanie.
And we'd laugh.
And it wouldn't have felt like a funeral.
Best engineer I have ever served with.
UHURA: I never told Hemmer...
but he reminded me a lot of my dad.
Always pushing me to see things from a new perspective.
Do better. be better.
Losing Hemmer...
hurts.
The people you love the most can cause you the most pain.
But it's the people you love that can mend your heart...
when you feel broken.
That's what Hemmer's purpose was.
To fix what is broken.
And he did.
[DOOR WHOOSHES OPEN]
CHAPEL: Spock.
Do not follow me.
What's going on?
- I'm warning you. back off!
Tell me what's going on.
I can't control it.
I've let something out.
Rage. Pain.
It's your emotions.
My mind has gotten weak.
No. no.
It doesn't make you weak. Spock.
It makes you human.
♪♪
So. I found the lead...
on Oriana's family.
Someone out there might be looking for her.
How strong of a lead?
Not very.
It's. uh. weak. actually.
And it's outside Federation space.
But you want to pursue it anyway?
I know what it feels like to be alone.
If there's any chance she still has people out there...
A mission like this...
it takes time.
I'd like to request a formal leave of absence.
Decommission me if you have to...
but I need the freedom to go where the clues take me.
If I said no. would it make a difference?
I...
I'll square it with Starfleet.
Whatever you need.
But. La'An...
however long it takes...
come back to us. okay?
Aye. sir.
Captain.
Chris.
Thank you.
For everything.
♪♪
[CONSOLE BEEPING SOFTLY]
%$%$
STAR TREK
STRANGE NEW WORLDS